### Contact

libertyrn7@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/annem-rendeiro-rn-bsn-bs-phnccrn-95369459 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Public Health

Vascular

**Medical Coding** 

## Languages

French

Spanish

#### Honors-Awards

Pedagogical Fellow University of California Irvine

Jonas Nurse Scholars Fellowship Award

Commendation

Invitation for Keynote Address

Graduate Student Nurse Policy Committee

# Anne M. Rendeiro, RN BSN BS PHN CCRN

Critical Care Registered Nurse at Fountain Valley Regional Hospital and Medical Center

Dana Point, California

# Summary

Educational preparation includes a BA from UCI in Social Ecology with minors in Psychology and Social Behavior as well as a BSN from USC in Nursing Science.

Work experience includes 17 years adult critical care bedside experience in SICU, MICU and Trauma Medicine. Additionally, functioned in several leadership roles focusing on strengthening multi-disciplinary team coordination and improving patient outcomes including: Rapid Response RN, code blue team, root cause analysis, tracer methodology, quality improvement and JCAHO/CADPH unit preparation. Also worked adjunct clinical faculty for both BSN and MSN Nursing students at the University level, where I discovered a passion for teaching.

Chosen to speak at the XXVII World Congress of The International Association for Suicide Prevention, Oslo Norway September, 2013. Topic encompassed suicide among the Dakota Sioux, which remain some of the highest rates worldwide. Poster Presentation at the 8th annual MUSC Conference on Health Disparities in Long Beach, CA. November 2014.

Clinical and research interests include knowledge synthesis and translation of best practices to indigenous communities, researchers and public policy-makers to improve health outcomes, morbidity and quality of life for these unique populations. Clinical Translational Science as a method for communicating best practices is also of great interest in the area of Health Disparities among NAAI populations because of the collaborative nature of the scientific approach directly with the Indigenous communities themselves as reservoirs of their own understanding. Indigenous populations continue to be impacted by the unseen political, social and

academic structures of colonization which impacts progress to true decolonization and health. I hope to bridge this gap in a manner that both pleases the science and the populations I serve.

# Experience

Fountain Valley Regional Hospital and Medical Center Critical Care Registered Nurse January 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months) Fountain Valley California

Concordia University Irvine
Adjunct Faculty Instructor
October 2017 - Present (2 years 9 months)

Orange County, California Area

Facilitate student learning, provide effective instruction, and perform evaluations of student performance outcomes in a clinical setting, using each course's clinical evaluation tool as a guide. Additionally facilitate student learning, provide effective instruction, and perform evaluations of student performance outcomes in a skills lab or simulation setting. Provide prompt and meaningful feedback to students in a fair, objective and consistent manner. Use established rubrics and clear grading criteria. Assign grades and maintain course/student records in accordance with FERPA regulations. Submit grades and records by established deadlines. Work collaboratively with the Department Chair or Program Director, faculty, staff, and students to advance the mission and academic excellence of the assigned School or College, in accordance with the mission, values and vision of CU.

California Board of Registered Nursing Department of Consumer Affairs

Expert Practice Consultant Enforcement Division March 2015 - Present (5 years 4 months)

Dana Point, California

Utilizing professional and educational background to review investigative case materials, prepare written opinions, evaluating whether an RN deviated from standards of nursing practice, or is responsible for unprofessional conduct according to the Nurse Practice Act.

RN CCRN April 2018 - October 2018 (7 months)

Mission Viejo, California

University of California Irvine
Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant
September 2013 - December 2016 (3 years 4 months)
Irvine, California

Responsible for assisting faculty of record for the undergraduate Program in Nursing Science at UCI, by lecturing, leading discussion, preparation of special topic lectures and general administrative record keeping on the Electronic Educational Environment (EEE) for students.

UC Irvine
PhD Student
July 2013 - December 2016 (3 years 6 months)
uc irvine graduate school of nursing

PhD student in Nursing Science with Cultural & Ethnic Disparities in Healthcare focus. Fellowships and awards for Jonas Nurse Leader Scholar, UCI Pedagogical Fellow, AACN-GNSA Policy Committee appointment for inaugural class in Washington DC.

University California Irvine Public Health RN, CCRN-K, PhD Student 2013 - 2016 (3 years)

California Baptist University
Adjunct Faculty
January 2013 - June 2013 (6 months)
riverside, calfornia

Taught first year students in the acute care clinical setting and skills lab for Nursing Fundamentals and Critical Care. Also taught EL-MSN students in the clinical setting for Adult Health II Critical Care. Directed students in the SIM lab creating simulated patient scenarios across the continuum of acute care. Top scores in student evaluations of faculty performance with 100% student participation.

Riverside Community Hospital RN, CCRN, SICU December 2010 - April 2013 (2 years 5 months) Formerly employed in the SICU as well as Rapid Response RN for hospital serving patients and their family along the continuum of care.

Inland Valley Medical Center RN,BSN, PHN March 2007 - December 2010 (3 years 10 months)

The candidate was a successful employee at Inland Valley Medical Center, a level II trauma center serving the Inland Empire demographic. Full scope of the nursing process required for adult and occasional pediatric critical care trauma patient. Routinely floated to ER, PACU and PCU as charge RN. Patient care routine to ICU setting including collaborative patient management, discharge planning and interfacility transfers when higher level of care warranted. Lead ICU peers in a team approach to rolling out a new policy based on best practice to reduce pressure ulcers in long-term trauma patients. Often took leadership role in precepting new nurses to ICU setting, frequently working with nursing students and new graduates.

# Riverside County Regional Medical Center RN, BSN

December 2003 - January 2007 (3 years 2 months)

Under direct supervision of the Assistant Nurse Manager, as a new grad, assess, diagnose, plan, implement and evaluate nursing care and interventions provided to the ICU patient. Routinely assess patients upon admission in a timely manner to include consideration of physical, psychosocial, cultural and spiritual needs. Also addresses education, pain management and discharge needs. Reviews and updates the plan of care on a daily basis. Excellent foundational experience as a new grad exemplifying the nurses expanded role in a busy County Hospital setting, including answering phones, secretarial work, answering doors, restocking and assisting in general unit duties.

\* Earlier work experience in acute medical and psychiatric care available upon request.

Honors/Publications:

Publication of undergraduate research paper. Knudsen, A. (1990, fall). Suicide and the Teton Dakota: A Durkheimian Analysis. Social Ecology Newsletter Division of Sociology and Psychology 10-17, excerpt.

Awarded Participation in Human Stress Seminar Class at the University of California Irvine. Invitation to only 6 students in class of 198

U.C.I. Medical Center

### RESEARCH ASSISTANT

January 1991 - August 1991 (8 months)

School of Social Ecology and California State Developmental Research Institute.

Completed project on Perinatal Stress Outcomes. This was a multidisciplinary research study designed to evaluate the magnitude of effects and mechanisms by which physical and psychological stress experienced by women during pregnancy impact the organization and development of the fetal/neonatal/infant brain structure and function. The candidate was the Senior Student Project Coordinator for the Medi-Cal Clinic at U.C.I.M.C. Bilingually recruited Spanish and English speaking subjects. Assisted in the evaluation of maternal and fetal health by conducting fetal heart rate monitoring, Doppler ultrasounds, collection and treatment of blood, urine and amniotic fluid samples for biochemical analysis. Also assisted in the evaluation of psychosocial stress and its moderators through structured interviews and questionnaires. Finally, evaluated environmental stress by interview and monitoring techniques for exposure to chemical teratogens, low frequency electromagnetic radiation, noise, crowding and lead.

# Education

University of Southern California
Bachelor of Science, Nursing (2001 - 2003)

### **UC Irvine**

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Social Ecology Minor Psychology Social Behavior · (1987 - 1991)